Frank G. Speck Papers 1903-1950 Mss.Ms.Coll.126
American Philosophical Society
- Subcollection I. Frank G. Speck Papers, 1897-1950; 10 linear feet
  - Series I. Research Material, 1903-1950; 8.25 linear feet
    - XIII. Miscellaneous
      - XV. Columbia Lecture Notes
        - Anthropology V and I, ca. 1904-1917; XV(24); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 16)
          Image note: 5 ink sketches of Churinga.
        - Culture and Chinook. Anthropology 707, Culture Dr. Boas, ca. 1904-1917; XV(24); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 16)
        - Ethnography of Asia, ca. 1904-1917; XV(24); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 16)
        - Iroquois languages, ca. 1904-1917; XV(24); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 16)
        - Klamath, Sioux, Chinook, ca. 1904-1917; XV(24); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 16)
        - Lecture notes of course with Boas, Tribes of North Pacific, ca. 1904-1917; XV(24); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 16)
        - Misc. Anthropology notebook, ca. 1904-1917; XV(24); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 16)
        - Misc. Anthropology notes, ca. 1904-1917; XV(24); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 16)
        - Science of language, West Asia, archaeology of Mexico, ca. 1904-1917; XV(24); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 17)
          Images note: 10 sketches of Aztec and Mayan stone figures, attire.
        - Tsimshian, ca. 1904-1917; XV(24); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 17)
        - Tsimshian and Eskimo, ca. 1904-1917; XV(24); 1 item; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (Box 17)
    - XIV. Natural History
      - Southeastern botanical specimens, 1938-1941; XIV(23a); 12 items (Box 15 & 32)
        Specimens of Coopti (Zamia poridana) used by Seminoles, 1941; Ilex vomitoria Ait, used by Creek. Letters to Speck from Richard Evans Schultes, April 25, 1938, A.L.S., 2p.; Feb. 8, 1938, A.L.S., 2p.; Feb. 9, 1941, T.L.S., 1p., all concerning Houma ethnobotany. Specimens are in Box 32.
        F&S 802
      - Botanical and zoological field observations, 1919-1942; XIV(23b); 3 items (Box 15)
        Field notebook and magazine clipping
      - [no entry], XIV(23c) (Box 15)
      - White mountains, n.d.; XIV(23d); 6 items (Box 15)
      - New Jersey Pine Barrens, 1914-1915; XIV(23e); 3 items (Box 15)
        [photographs in red notebook]
      - Drawings, n.d.; XIV(23f); 2 items (Box 15)
        Images note: 3 ink sketches of drinking cups of Squash-Passukey.
      - Some Observations on Serpents, n.d.; XIV(23g); 1 item (Box 15)
        [typed document, no folder]
  - Series II. Biographical Material, 1897-1950; 1.75 linear feet
    Images note: 14 illustrations of Pamunkey and Cayuga rattles, Cherokee mask, Toltec designs, and logos of thunderbird, tipi; 1 photograph of Frank Speck in sled at Maniwaki, P.Q.(from William Fenton); 3 photographs of Anthony Wallace at Dismal run.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1926 June 26; 2 items; Academy of Natural Sciences (Box 17)
      Letter and credentials stating Speck is a delegate of the Academy to the International Congress of Americanists held in Rome.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1915; 3 items; Aitken, Robert (Box 17)
      Letters regarding Aitken's accepting the position in the Department at the University of Pennsylvania which Speck arranged, and the plans for his summer voyage to Puerto Rico with Boas. Formal letter accepting the position.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1949; 2 items; Alexander, James Evan (Box 17)
      Photocopies of letters between Speck and Alexander regarding the Indians near Lake Waccamaw. Source of letters typed at top.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1905-1944; 18 items; American Anthropological Association. (Box 17)
      Correspondence regarding Speck's election as a member, and nomination to various Councils, list of officers for the American Anthropological Association. Notification that he has been elected Vice-President of the AAA for one year.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1916-1939; 2 items; American Association for the Advancement of Science. (Box 17)
      Notification of election. Notification that he has been elected Section Committeeman for the Section on Anthropology (H).
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1907 February 4; 1 item; American Ethnological Society (Box 17)
      Notification of election
    - n.d., 1 item; American Folklore Society. (Box 17)
      Typed Table of contents for a handbook.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1923; 1 item; American Indian Order (Box 17)
      Membership card.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1903-1918; 6 items; American Museum of Natural History. (Box 17)
      Authorization to conduct research, and acknowledgement of gifts.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1917; 3 items; American Sociological Society (Box 17)
      Regarding Specks presentation of a paper at the 1917 annual meeting of the Society in Philadelphia.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1913-1915; 2 items; Ames, Herman Vandenburg, 1865-1935 (Box 17)
      Appologies for the delay in replying to Speck. Regarding the issue of Gordon having Speck's library removed from his office in the Museum. Thanking Speck for sending copies of his latest publication.
    - to Editor, 1935; 3 items; Amsden, Charles Avery, 1899-1941 (Box 17)
      Announcment of interst to readers regarding the Frederick Webb Hodge Anniversary publication.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1940; 1 item; Archaeological Society of North Carolina (Box 17)
      Notification he has been eleced an honorary member
    - to Frank G. Speck, n.d.; 1 item; Bailey, A. G. (Box 17)
      Sending a copy of his book on Algonquians to Speck.
      F&S 4109
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1942; 1 item; Ball, Carl C. (Box 17)
      Sending Speck a price for items he sent him. Is interested in obtaining more information on the Southeastern material culture of indians.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1945; 1 item; Barbeau, Marius, 1883-1969 (Box 17)
      Thanks Speck for sending him a piece of old silver found in a grave. Believes the piece to have been made in Quebec City between 1800 and 1830.
    - From Frank G. Speck, 1948; 1 item; Bates, George Joesph, 1891- (Box 17)
      Letter to Bates regarding legislation to reduce wildlife preservation, particularly the Parker River Refuge.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1913-1914; 2 items; Battles, Frank (Box 17)
      Acknowledges previous letters. Recommends he contact Dr. Harrison.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1941; 1 item; Beatty, Willard W. (Willard Walcott), 1891-1961 (Box 17)
      Concerning field work among the Houma Indians.
      F&S 1571
    - from Frank G. Speck, 1927; 1 item; Bennett, Foster (Box 17)
      Regarding the purchase of and shipping instructions for three birch-bark canoes and two pairs of paddles.
      F&S 4148
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1940-1941; 4 items; Beston, Henry and Elizabeth Coatsworth Beston (Box 17)
      Concerning Montagnais reminiscences, Indian pough; Main Indans, Joe Pye weed, etc.
      F&S 2289
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1938; 1 item; Bever, Marion G. (Box 17)
      Mrs. Bever is writing a historh of Mashpee, Mass. and is contacting Speck for information regarding the Indians of the area.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1936; 1 item; Bingham, M (Box 17)
      Thanks Speck for the pamphlet "Penobscot Tales and Religious ?"
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1930-1932; 10 items; Birket-Smith, Kaj, 1893-1977 (Box 17)
      Letters concern specimens sent by Speck to Danish Museum (Copenhagen National Museum).
      F&S 1245
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1944; 1 item; Blackwood, Beatrice (Box 17)
      Appologizes for sending out the Museum Report for the Pitt Rivers Museum, University of Oxford. Comments on how the war has effected their efforts in publication.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1937; 1 item; Blakeley, A. W. (Box 17)
      Is a graduate student at the University of Toronto. Inquires where he can obtain a copy of Speck's work on Ojibawa, and if Speck can be of additional help.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1947; 1 item; Bloom, Leonard, 1927- (Box 17)
      Concerning his manuscript on Cherokee Dances; seeks names for dances.
      F&S 599
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1904 - 1938; 27 items; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942 (Box 17)
      Letter recommending Speck for a scholarship; letter in regards to Aitkens; letters regarding receiving papers for meeting, and Boas' visit with Speck in Philadelphia. Concerning copying of his Catawba texts; concerning Cherokee field work of Frans Olbrechts. Materials relating to the American Council of Learned Societies on Research in American Native Languages, principally consisting of reports on grants and their progress. Report of Committee on Research in Native American Languages, listing vanishing languages studied, by whom, publications, materials to be published, work to be done, and expenditures. Regarding criticism of the Executive Section of the Committee on Research in Native American Languages to the American Council of Learned Societies. Cover letter for a check to Speck. Asks Speck to write a letter on behalf of his sister Hedwig Lehmann who is 75, and wants to immigrate to the U.S.
      F&S 686, 1976, 4270
    - From Frank G. Speck, 1929; 1 item; Bogoras, W. (Box 17)
      Regarding his proposition for exchange students between the University and Russia.
    - from Frank G. Speck, 1925; 1 item; Bond, Charles E. (Box 17)
      Regarding references for information on the Indians of Maine. Mentions Chief Frances and A. V. Kidder.
      F&S 4478
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1914; 1 item; Brimley, C. S. (Box 17)
      Invoice with note regarding Specks purchase of snakes.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1936; 1 item; Britten, Marian Hale (Box 17)
      Regarding Speck's reappointment to Committee on Survey of South American Indians, National Research Council.
      F&S 4739
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1945; 1 item; Buck, John Lossing, 1890-1975 (Box 17)
      Received book, and will send mask some time soon.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1946; 1 item; Buffalo Museum of Science (Box 17)
      Notification that he has been elected an honorary Charter Member in appreciation of his contributions.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1904-1924; 2 items; Bureau of American Ethnology (Box 17)
      1904 letter authorizing Speck to incur expenses for his work in connection to the Handbook of American Languages. 1924 letter regarding Specks Calusa proposition.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1945; 1 item; Burgesse, J. Allan (Box 17)
      Regarding difficulty of obtaining crooked knives, birch-bark baskets, etc., for Speck; Burgesse's work on the translation form the French of Eugene Roy's diarly (including Sumner's battle with Cheyennes and descriptions of other Indians).
      F&S 4271
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1934; 2 items; Chase, Fannie S. (Box 17)
      Concerning research on and publication of material on Maine Indians. Comments regarding the impact of the Depression on scholarly publication.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1946; 1 item; Chester, Allan G. (Allan Griffith), 1900- (Box 17)
      Acknowledges receiving recent article.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1915; 1 item; Child, C. G. (Box 17)
      Thanking Speck for his two monographs, and commenting on a discussion they had the previous Spring.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1944; 2 items; Cobb, Rodney D. (Box 17)
      Contacts Speck to obtain copies of his publications on birch-bark techniques.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1930-1931; 2 items; Cole, Fay-Cooper, 1881-1961 (Box 17)
      Concerning exhibits for Chicago World's Fair.
      F&S 1421
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1904-1905; 3 items; Columbia University. (Box 17)
      Notification of Specks appointment as University Scholar in Anthropology and President's University Scholar in Anthropology, and that he has received his Masters degree.
    - To Frank G. Speck, 1947; 1 item; Comas, Juan (Box 17)
      Asking Speck to cotribute to the Boletin Bibliografico de Antropologia Americana.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1945-1949; 2 items; Congdon, Charles E., (Charles Edwin), b. 1877 (Box 17)
      Concerning Coldspring Long House ceremonies; use of stick and post in dance; Tonawanda and Cattaraugus medicines.
      F&S 3242
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1942; 1 item; Cooper, John M., (John Montgomery), 1881-1949 (Box 17)
      Thanks Speck for sending the paper Speck wrote with Eiseley on Montagnais-Naskapi Bands. Comments on its relation to his work Temporal Sequence and Marginal Cultures (Catholic University of America. Anthropological series, no. 10, 1941).
    - to Frank G. Speck, n.d.; 1 item; Crawford, J. W. (Box 17)
      Thanks him for sending article.
    - n.d., 1 item; Crow Court, The (Box 17)
      Handwritten story.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1915; 1 item; Daniel, W.B.M. (Box 17)
      Note of thanks for the work on jade Speck provided him, and his wish he had more training in anthropology.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1924; 1 item; Darlington, H. S. (Box 17)
      Recounts his experience of observing a snake swallow its young and a toad shed its skin after reading Speck's article in the Journal of American Foldlroe.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1931; 1 item; Davidson, Thomas, 1817-1885 (Box 17)
      one word telegram - "Accepted"
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1947; 2 items; Day, Gordon M. (Box 17)
      Regarding obtaining a copy of Speck's Penobscot Transformer Texts. Day is a forester who is contacting Speck to obtain information on his study of Indian occupation and place names in Vermont.
      F&S 4656
    - from Frank G. Speck, 1947; 1 item; Deardorff, Merle H., d.1971 (Box 17)
      Concerning Iroquois conference at Allegany.
      F&S 3277
    - n.d., 1 item; Definitions for Clan from Various Sources (Box 17)
      List of 9 definitions for clan, and 6 definitions for Moiety, Phratry, Dual Division.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1928-1932; 7 items; Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony. Correspondence regadring (Box 17)
      Correspondence regarding the publication of, and commends regarding Speck's work Delaware Indian Big House Ceremony. Correspondents include John W. Cooper, Franz Boas, William A. Slaughter, and Robert W. Reader.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1922; 1 item; Department of Justice, Canada (Box 17)
      Letter from the deputy minister of justice requesting information from Speck regarding the indians of the Labrador coast, as it pertains to a court case. On verso is Speck's reply.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1949; 1 item; Deskaheh, Alexander General (Box 17)
      Extract prepared for William Fenton, concerning slaughter of the Hurons by the Iroquois, together with Speck's notes on historical sources.
      F&S 1702
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1947; 1 item; Dimmick, Edgar R. (Box 17)
      Replies to Speck regarding his family history.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1920; 1 item; Dixon, Joseph K. (Box 17)
      Indicates his willingness to see Speck and discuss his work at hand.
    - Report of the Division of Athropology and Psychology for the Year 1922-1923, 1 item; Dodge, Raymond, 1871-1942 (Box 17)
      Report of division, with addition listing members.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1938; 1 item; Dorrance, Frances, b. 1877 (Box 17)
      Informing Speck that he has been elected a director of the Society for Pennsylvania Archaeology for a three year term.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1939-1943; 6 items; Douglas, Frederic H. and Frances Raynolds (Box 17)
      Letters to Speck regarding his sending artifacts to the Denver Art Museum, and Frederic Douglas's purchasing of them, and latter finanical difficulites.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1945; 1 item; Drake, Charley G. (Box 17)
      Requesting a copy of "Gourds of the Southeastern Indians"; payment enclosed.
      F&S 4763
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1935; 1 item; Dunnack, Henry E. (Box 17)
      States that the Maine State Library has Symbolism in Penobscot Art and Wawenock Myth Texts and has ordered Naskapi. Anticipates Speck's new volume on Maine Indians.
      F&S 4278
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1938-1948; 6 items; Dutcher, Willena B. and Frederic H. Douglas (Box 17)
      Concerning acquisition of material-culture specimens for the Denver Art Museum: New England, Virginia, Tunica, etc. Concerning acquisition of material-culture specimens for the Denver Art Museum: New England, Virginia, Tunica, etc.
      F&S 1247
    - to Frank G. Speck and Henry E. Dunnack, 1935; 2 items; Eckstorm, Fannie Hardy, 1865-1946 (Box 18)
      Regarding financial support for publication of Speck's manuscript on Penobscot social and economic life.
      F&S 4657
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1915; 1 item; Edgerton, Franklin, 1885-1963 (Box 18)
      Expresses appreciation for copies of some of Speck's publications.
      F&S 4279
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1947; 1 item; Edwards, Edgar Van W. (Box 18)
      Sending Speck postcards. Comments on Dr. and Mrs. Macy who collected them.
    - To Frank G. Speck, 1946; 1 item; Edwards, William Waller (Box 18)
      Acknowledging receipt of Speck's letter on the Yankwis.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1934-1945; 3 items; Eiseley, Loren P. (Box 18)
      Concerning Speck's contribution to anthropology: concerning mention of scapulimancy in Drake (1839). Concerning Speck's contribution to anthropology; concerning mention of scapulimancy in Drake (1839). Fragment of letter regarding the exchange of articles with Speck.
      F&S 1249
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1935; 1 item; Eisenberger, E. (Box 18)
      Concerning scapulimancy and spread of the custom.
      F&S 1250
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1943-1944; 3 items; Eskew, James W. (Box 18)
      Requests information on publications relating to American Indians, e.g., about the mounds of the Mississippi and Ohio valleys and about the Cliff Dwellers and Pueblos of the Southwest. Regarding Speck's pamphlets on specific topics.
      F&S 4280
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1930; 1 item; Farabee, William Curtis, 1865-1925 (Box 18)
      Requsts that Speck sends someone to read his paper. Refers to Speck's request fo his manuscript.
    - Recommendations for Scholarship, 1904-1905; 2 items; Farrand, Livingston, 1867-1939 (Box 18)
      Letter of recommendation for Speck's scholarship application.
    - to Frank Speck, 1936-1950; 67 items; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005 (Box 18)
      Concerning field work among Catawba, Cherokee, and Houma; principally, however, Fenton's Seneca field work and Speck's various studies of the Iroquois. 3 letters pertain to Mahican (Stockbridge) texts recorded by Truman Michelson. Relations of Delaware and Iroquois. Some materials on Iroquois conferences prior to 1950. [note, photograph] Post card congratulating speck on his publication of The Delaware Indians as Women. "A Newsletter to the Second Conference on Iroquois Research" - Newsletter regarding events at the conference.
      F&S 1660
    - to Frank G. Speck, n.d.; 1 item; Ferris, R. H. (Box 18)
      Poem written to Speck after a stay at his home.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1921-1923; 3 items; Fewkes, Jesse Walter, 1850-1930 (Box 18)
      Directions and instructions for Catawba field trips made by Speck for the Bureau of American Ethnology.
      F&S 507
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1946-1947; 2 items; Field, Clark (Box 18)
      Regarding his personal collection of Indian baskets.
    - to Frank G. Speck, n.d.; 1 item; Finkelstein, Elsie (Box 18)
      Comments on remembering a ceremony[?]
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1934; 1 item; Ford, C. Desmond, (Charles Desmond) (Box 18)
      Thanks Speck for a copy of the Penobscot Manuscript. Has received it too late to use it as source material for his pending book.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1914; 1 item.; Fry, Nat P. (Box 18)
      Verification of shipping his order of snakes.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1947; 1 item; Gamio, Manuel, 1883-1960 (Box 18)
      Acknowledges receipt of Creek Indian pamphlet.
      F&S 790
    - to C. M. Barbeau, 1926; 1 item; Gandy, Ethel (Box 18)
      Expressing appreciation for names of chiefs and their clans. Regarding the reproduction by Wissler of plates for Gandy's forthcoming monograph on Penobscot art.
      F&S 4658
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1914; 1 item; Garner, Alfred B. (Box 18)
      Disputes Speck's article stating that snakes will swallow their young in times of danger, based on his own observation.
    - from Frank G. Speck, 1928-1929; 2 items; Gauthier, E. S. (Box 18)
      Regarding the meaning of the Indian name Pizendawach; purchase of a bow and arrow by Speck. Mentions Andre Cayer.
      F&S 4331
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1914-1915; 2 items; Geographical Society of Philadelphia. (Box 18)
      First letter informs Speck that he has been elected a member, and the second informs him he has been selected to serve on the Committee on Study and Research.
    - From AS, 1927; 1 item; Geyelin and Company (Box 18)
      Has received communications, and thanks him for the refund.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1940; 1 item; Giger, Leona E. (Box 18)
      Student at Haskell Institute writes concerning a Creek doll she is making; mentions council house at Okmulgee, Oklahoma.
      F&S 791
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1945; 1 item; Gilliam, Charles Edgar (Box 18)
      Letter of introduction for William B McIlwaine III to Speck.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1931; 1 item; Gilmore, Melvin R., (Melvin Randolph), 1868-1940 (Box 18)
      Concerning ethnobotanical exhibits for the Chicago World's Fair.
      F&S 1427
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1914; 1 item; Gisriel, Stewart W. (Box 18)
      Booking of a lecture for Speck.
    - Check, 1922; 1 item; Gloucester Safe Deposit and Trust Co. (Box 18)
      Personal check issued by Speck.
    - from Frank G. Speck, 1929; 1 item; Godcharles, Frederic Antes, 1872- (Box 18)
      Regarding the shipment of Godcharles of Delaware Indian specimens received from War Eagle.
      F&S 4224
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1916; 1 item; Goddard, Pliny Earle, 1869-1928 (Box 18)
      Pertaining to Mechling's review of Speck.
      F&S 2291
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1913-1917; 8 items; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940 (Box 18)
      Returning Speck's manuscript. Concerning Goldenweiser's review and that of Mechling of Speck. Responses to Speck's letter, suggests the best time to meet. Also gives a list of subjects which Speck mith want to look into. Regarding his meeting with Speck, must reschedule until January. Agrees to speak at Speck's seminar. Appologizes for disappointing Speck, was not able to get away because Mrs. Goldenweiser was sick. Telegram stating he cannot come. Happy to stay with Speck after coming up to give a Lecture to Aitken's class.
      F&S 2292
    - from Frank G. Speck, 1929; 1 item; Goldfrank, Esther (Box 18)
      Concerning "clown" performances outside of the southwest among Penobscot, Iroquois, Abenaki, and Delaware.
      F&S 2930
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1913-1924; 15 items; Gordon, G. B., (George Byron), 1870-1927 (Box 18)
      Regarding Speck and the museum (access to early, and obtaining books). Concerning publication of Speck's Penobscot materials. Concerning the submission of Speck's manuscript of "Life and Culture of the Penobscot Indians" for publication by the University, and a latter request by Speck to have the manuscript back to make changes. List by Speck of incidents with Gordon.
      F&S 2931
    - Gourds in the Southeast (Box 18)
      scrapbook with clippings of reviews.
    - To Frank G. Speck, 1947; 1 item; Great Northern Railway Company (Box 18)
      Reply to Specks request for the 1947 Indian calendar.
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1929-1947; 4 items; Greywacz, Kathryn B. (Box 18)
      1929 - Regarding possible purchase from Speck of some modern Delaware items; request for pictures of those pieces; Speck's reply. 1947 - Regarding proposed sale of some of Speck's baskets from Eastern American Indian groups. Notice of his election as an honorary member of the Archaeological Society of New Jersey.
      F&S 4216, 4239
    - to Frank G. Speck, 1926-1939; 5 items; Gusinde, Martin, 1886-1969 (Box 18)